Hello friends, my name is Anil Rajpurohit.
I am a finance and founder of Family
First Financial Services.
Today I am presenting to you
HDFC Life Insurance's Cancer Care,
a health insurance plan. The company
is a life insurance company but they have a health
insurance plan called Cancer
Care. Here you will see the features of this plan
that whether you have early stage
cancer or major stage cancer, you get the benefit
and you get lump sum
benefits. This policy
is a benefit policy and not an Indian policy. What happens in the policy is
that suppose you get cancer and get
admitted in the hospital, your bill came for Rs. 5 lakh and you
got Rs. 5 lakh but there is nothing like that here.
If your insurance is for Rs. 25
lakh and you are diagnosed with cancer, then you
get Rs. 2500000 at once. The policy is
banked and you do not have any medical insurance cover in it.
In this policy, you will be given three options:
Silver, Gold, Platinum. I will
talk about the base plan and the Silver plan in
which you normally take one insurance plan of Rs. 20,
25, 30, 50.  You
can take insurance up to Rs.10 lakh to Rs.50
lakh, so
this is the base benefit in all three options, but if you want
your insurance tax to increase by 10% over time, you can
take the Golden Platinum plan,
and if you want to get 1%
of your insurance tax every month
for the next 5 years, then you can take the Platinum plan,
but the
more you add these options, the more
your premium will increase, so I would recommend you to take the
Silver plan if you are not able to afford it,
and if you look here,
I will tell you two-three more things,
you will not get any benefit in this, you will not get any maturity benefit, you will
not get any Surrender benefit,
this is a health insurance policy and
after taking this policy, it is not like you
purchased the policy today on 16th August 2023 and
you left the company on 20th August 2013, so it is done,
give me the money,
you cannot make a claim for 180 days after taking the policy,
after that you can make a claim
and there is no survival benefit for this
This commando of the period is of seven days,
after you are diagnosed,
you should survive for at least 7 days, it is not that you get
cancer and die the next day,
this will not happen because cancer does
not happen immediately, it is not a heart attack,
if you survive for 7 days then you will get the
claim and it is not that you make an early
claim, you
cannot claim within 6 months, like
in medical insurance you make a claim after 30 days,
similarly in this policy you have to pay Rs. 180, that is,
after 6 months you become
eligible to claim in it and you will
also get the benefit of free look in it, you have a
free look of 30 days, if you do not want to
take the policy then you can cancel it, there
is a premium guarantee, premium guarantee
means that in the policy which is your health
insurance, this type of policy is being given by this live company, in that
your
premium will not increase with time and age, if you
take a health insurance policy then you know
that your premium gets revised after every 5 years,
but there is something like this in it  There will
also be no portability in this policy.
Even though HDFC Life
Insurance is selling the policy,
its feature is related to health, so if you
want to port the policy to another company, you can do it.
You will not get any loan etc. in this policy. Now, in
early stage cancer, you all know
what happens, major stage cancellation etc.
You all know what relief is there in this.
Now I will try to explain to you through a registration. There is
a person of 35 years and
he wants to take a policy for 15 years. He is paying a tax of Rs
25 lakh and
his premium is without GST. 1947 is 15th
August. We got independence on 1947. So,
you too can get freedom from the
tension of expenses arising from your cancer by taking this premium.
This premium is very lucky. 1947 independence.
Now you will see that here
I have kept silver plain and 1947 GST in it is
18%. See, Rs 2297 will
remain Rs 2297 for 15 years. The premium will
not increase with time.  If cancer
is diagnosed
[Music]
Now here I will try to tell you
that your future age is 30, 35, 40 or 45
years. If you are taking insurance for 10 years,
15 years or 20 years, then your
premium for a 30 year old person, if he is
taking insurance for 10 years for 25 lakhs, then his
premium will be 140051 and if you are taking it for 15 years then it will be
1543 and if you are taking it for 20 years then it will be
17 if you are 35 then you
can see it this way, if you are 40 years old
then you can see the premium, it
is quite cheap, I can say that suppose
you are 30 years old and now you take insurance for the next 20
years i.e. till 50 years for 1700, by then
your children etc. will have grown up, your
savings will be reduced to a great extent,
otherwise suppose if it gets cancelled then the expenditure of 25 lakhs will be incurred.
How much your entire savings will be lost
but this is a premium of Rs 1700 per year,
so you can make this call and get yourself
treated and get cured,
thank you so match,
if you liked my video then before
leaving do subscribe to the channel, thank
you so match